Alec Sharp

10 years experience working with people, 4 years experience working with data (mostly in Python).

I am passionate about bridging the gap between people and data.

I am looking to join a collaborative environment to help build awesome things.

Website	Github	LinkedIn
alecsharpie.me	github.com/alecsharpie	linkedin.com/in/alecsharpie

Work Experience

Lead Data Science Teacher @ Le Wagon

<u>lewagon.com</u>	Melbourne, Australia.	Feb 2021 - Present (1y 7m)

- Taught in Python: analysis & statistics, machine learning, deep learning, and containerised deployment.
- Coordinated and guided students' final projects: ML model, API, CI/CD.
- Collaborated on developing and maintaining the bootcamp's curriculum & educational resources.
- Gave lectures, worked 1 on 1 with students, and live coded with groups of up to 30. Inperson and remotely.
- Effectively managed student engagement and satisfaction and received an average rating of 9.5/10.

Data Scientist @ Mindsets Learning

mindsets.com	Melbourne, Australia.	Oct 2019 - Apr 2021 (1y 7m)

- Extracted and transformed sensitive cloud data to create reliable & fresh reporting and training data.
- Trained statistical and machine learning models to interpret or predict valuable data points.
- Designed customer facing reports & dashboards to communicate KPI's to stakeholders.
- Mapped the users' experience, and leveraged this data to identify pain points and unlock value propositions.

Alec Sharp 1

- Automated reports for the marketing & sales teams, saving weeks of their time.
- Orchestrated the onboarding of new data scientists into the product and business development teams.

Research Intern @ Work With Nature

work-with-nature.com Parcelas San Miguel, Costa Rica. May 2019 - Jun 2019 (lm)
--	-----

- Explored statistical models to help develop a biodiversity assessment for evaluating property purchases.
- Developed a data entry protocol to ensure future data will be in the most practical format.
- Guided students through statistical processes for their research.

Data Analyst @ Hoffman & Ospina Landscape Architecture

hoffmanospina.com Los Angeles, United States. Mar 2019 - May 2019 (3m)
--

- Evaluated the companies' data assets, and processed them to facilitate a meaningful analysis.
- Implemented statistical models to provide insights on how to optimise employee efficiency.
- Communicated business insights to key decision makers.

Inventory Analyst @ Rolling Greens, Home + Garden

<u>rghomeandgarden.com</u> Los Angeles, United States. Jun 2018 - Apr 2019 (1y)	
---	--

- Implemented statistical models to explain relationships to KPI's and help make decisions.
- Modelled Time series data to help predict inventory flow.
- Monitored the data from a newly established store, and delivered insights to executives.
- Maintained a balanced, aesthetically pleasing, and spatially efficient inventory of live goods.
- Communicated between departments: stock information, new processes, and operations.

Skills

Tech	Data Science	Engineering	Teamwork	Business
Python	Statistics	Google Cloud Platform	Git	Doc's, Sheet's, & Slides
R	Machine Learning	Docker	Zoom	Google

Alec Sharp 2

Tech	Data Science	Engineering	Teamwork	Business
SQL	Deep Learning	API's	Slack	Landing Page's
HTML & CSS	NLP	CI/CD	Communication	Saas
Bash	Computer Vision		Problem Solving	EdTech
	Data Viz		Adaptability	
	Storytelling			

Education

Bachelor of Science, Zoology & Statistics @ Otago University

www.otago.ac.nz	Dunedin, New Zealand.	Feb 2014 - Dec 2017 (4y)	

- Found a love for statistics in its applicability on data collected about the natural world.
- Honed my experimental design skills.

Alec Sharp 3